Matthew Cottrell

ClassicCottrell.ca

ClassicCottrell@gmail.com

**** 778-232-4629



My name is Matt and I'm a UI/UX designer. I've been in the software industry for 5 years. When I'm not at work, I'm either involved in film production, drawing weird cartoon characters, or reminiscing about my printing days, when I had access to a vinyl plotter, huge screens and endless rolls of paper.



Experience

- 5 years in a start-up environment
- Outgoing & positive personality
- Enthusiastic & dedicated learner
- Adapts easily to new situations & people
- I work well independently, however, I love working in a team environment & brainstorming with my colleagues.

Work History

Tagga - Creative Lead

UI/UX Lead 2016 - present

- User stories, Site mapping, Conception of new platform tools
- Creation of Low Fidelity to High Fidelity designs through wireframes, sketches, design, mockups, prototyping (pencil paper, adobe XD)
- Software theme & branding, element styles (color exploration, fonts, icons)

Lead Design UI/UX 2011 - 2016

- User Experience flow creation
- User Interface front-end development
- Cross Channel Campaign Strategy
- Design & creation of media for campaigns (in-store print design, facebook/ Instagram/twitter social posts, & responsive websites)
- Front End Development and QA for site deployments
- Social Community Creation
- Social posting and storytelling

Intern

2011

- Video production

video production

C2 Imaging- Sign Maker

- 2000 2010
- Large Format Digital Print Operator
- Lün Cutter Press Operator
- Saturn 5 Colour Printing Press Assistant

- HTML, CSS

Skills

UI/UX Design & Coding

- Foundation, Bootstrap, SASS, LESS

- Adobe Experience design

- Responsive design

- Email template creation

- Campaign Monitor & MailChimp

- Facebook Ad Manager

- Google Adwords

••••

••000

Art & Design

- Adobe Creative suite

- Photoshop- Illustrator

- InDesign

- Video Final Cut & After Effects

- Lighting & Set Design

- Classical 2D Animation

- Stop Motion & Cinemagraphs GIF's

	OC)
)

•••••

●●000 ●●000

Print & Layout

- Sign maker (layout and quality control)

- 5 color printing process

- T-shirt printing process

- Store Front vinyl sign application

- Zün (digital die-cutting)

- Prepress knowledge & understanding



•••00

•••00

•••00

Education and Training

BCIT - New Media Design & Web Development Certificate

Vancouver Film School - Foundation in Film & Design

Langley Fine Arts School - Fine Arts Major

2010 - 2011 2006 - 2007

2001 - 2004